Solley mss., 1888-2006 LMC 2885
Lilly Library
Solley mss.
1888-2006
Lilly Library
Solley, Thomas T.
LMC 2885
35 Boxes
The Solley mss., 1888-2006, consists of the automobile and coachbuilder catalogs, photographs, and related automobile literature of architect Thomas T. Solley, 1924–2006.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired: 2002-2003
Biographical Note
Born in New York City, Solley served in the U.S. Army, European Theatre from 1943–1946. In 1950, he received his B.A. in Architecture from Yale University, and pursued graduate studies at that institution prior to leaving in 1951 to become an Architectural Project Engineer at Eli Lilly & Co. in Indianapolis from 1951–1961. A grandnephew of Josiah K. Lilly, Solley left private practice as an architect to pursue a graduate degree in Art History at Indiana University earning an M.A. in 1966. In 1968, he was appointed Assistant Director of the Indiana University Art Museum in Bloomington becoming its Director in 1971. During Solley's tenure (1971-1986), the Art Museum's holdings grew from 4,000 to more than 30,000 works of art. In recognition of his service and commitment to the Art Museum as administrator, academic, and philanthropist, Solley was awarded the first Indiana University Medal (1982) and the President's Medal for Excellence (1997). In 2002, Indiana University awarded him an honorary Doctor of Fine Arts degree. Solley passed away in 2006 at his home in St. Prex, Switzerland.
Scope and Contents
The collection is arranged by the following series: I. Automobile Catalogs; II. Coachbuilder Catalogs; III. Miscellaneous. Catalogs are geographically arranged with automobile/coachbuilder catalogs alphabetically listed (in chronological order) within the grouping. Photographs, articles, and renderings, among other items (where identified) have been filed with the automobile/coachbuilder.
As a youth, Solley became interested in automobile and coachbuilder catalogs and spent more than 60 years systematically amassing a collection of them focused on the "automobile as art." The catalogs served as the basis for his 2008 monograph Prestige, Status, and Works of Art: Selling the Luxury Car 1888-1942, in which many of them are described in fulsome detail. Solley, also a discriminating collector of luxury automobiles (most notably Rolls-Royce and Bentley), did not limit his catalog collecting solely to Great Britain although these makes et al. are particularly well represented. The collection is also particularly strong in automobile and coachbuilder catalogs from France (Bugatti, Delage, Hispano-Suiza; Henri Chapron, J. Saoutchik), Germany (Horch, Mercedes-Benz; Glaserkarosserie G.M.B.H.), Italy (Alfa Romeo, Isotta Fraschini, Lancia; Castagna), and the United States (Cadillac, Chrysler, Lincoln, Packard; Fleetwood, LeBaron).
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by the following series: I. Automobile Catalogs; II. Coachbuilder Catalogs; III. Miscellaneous. Catalogs are geographically arranged with automobile/coachbuilder catalogs alphabetically listed (in chronological order) within the grouping. Photographs, articles, and renderings, among other items (where identified) have been filed with the automobile/coachbuilder.
Related Materials
When applicable, items have been linked to entries in Solley's monograph, Prestige, Status, and Works of Art: Selling the Luxury Car 1888-1942 (Lilly TL15 .S68 2008), by use of the notation SE (Solley Entry) along with the corresponding location within the text.
Automobiles --History --Pictorial works.; Solley, Thomas T.
- Automobile Catalogs
  Arrangement
  Arranged geographically, with catalogs alphabetically listed in chronological order within the grouping.
  - Australia (Box 1)
    - Holden, Road Tests (Box 1)
    - Thomson, Photographs (Box 1)
  - Austria
    - Austro Daimler, "Austro-Daimler"(SE: 2/51), 1914 (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, "Austro-Daimler"(SE: 4/382), c. 1921 (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, "Austro Daimler 6 Zylinger Tourenwagen"(SE: 6/384), c. 1923 (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, "Austro Daimler Type AD"(SE: 7/385), 1924 (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, "La Six Cylindres Austro Daimler Type ADV...", 1925 (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, "AD Austro Daimler...Types ADM 1970 HP...", 1926 (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, "ADM Sport 3 Litre"(SE: 11/710a), 1927 (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, "3 Liter ADR 11/70 H.P.", 1927-1928 (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, "Das Wunder des ADR"(SE: 12/711), 1929 (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, "Austro Daimler 12/70...", 1929 (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, "Type ADR 22/70 H.P.", 1929 (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, "Austro Daimler Alpine 8", 1930-1931 (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, "A New Austro Daimler Eight", 1930 (Oct. 7) (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, "Austro Daimler 3 Liter..."(SE: 15/714), 1932 (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, "Austro Daimler Bergmeister"(SE: 16/715), 1932 (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, "Austro Daimler Bergmeister"(SE: 17/1055), 1933 (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, Photographs (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, Renderings (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, Misc. (Box 1)
    - Fiat-Werke A.G. Wien, "Fiat–Werke A.–G. Wien"(SE: 1/53), 1915 (Box 1)
    - Graf & Stift, "Wiener Automobil Fabrik..."(SE: 1/54), 1912 (Box 1)
    - Graf & Stift, "Blueprints", c. 1930(?) (Box 1)
    - Graf & Stift, "Graf and Stift"(SE: 4/717), 1931 (Box 1)
    - Graf & Stift, "Type MF6 – Type G36", 1936 (Box 1)
    - Graf & Stift, "C12 Prototype"(photograph), 1938 (Box 1)
    - Graf & Stift, Misc. (Box 1)
    - Steyr, "Steyr Type VII"(SE: 2/390), 1924 (Box 1)
    - Steyr, "Steyr 14 HP Six Cylinder, Type XII", c. 1927 (Box 1)
    - Steyr, "Steyr Sport"(SE: 4/718) (photocopy), 1927-1928 (Box 1)
    - Steyr, "10 CV.6 Cylindres Type XII"(SE: 8/722), 1929 (Box 1)
    - Steyr, "10 CV, Type XII Six Cylindres", c. 1930(?) (Box 1)
    - Steyr, "8/40 PS 6 Zyl. 2 Lit."(SE: 10/724), 1930 (Box 1)
    - Steyr, "Steyr Cabriolet 32/45 CV Type 30S"(SE: 11/725), c. 1932 (Box 1)
    - Steyr, "TYP 630", 1936 (Box 1)
    - Steyr, "TYP 630", 1938 (Box 1)
    - Steyr, Misc. (Box 1)
    - Austro Daimler, "Automobiles, Austro Daimler" (SE: 5/383), c. 1923 (Box 24 (Oversize))
  - Belgium
    - Excelsior, "Excelsior"(SE: 3/392), 1922-1923 (Box 1)
    - Excelsior, "Excelsior", 1922-1923 (Box 1)
    - Excelsior, "Excelsior…Made in Belgium" (SE: 7/727), c. 1928 (Box 1)
    - Excelsior, "Albert I, Chassis 6 Cylindres de Grand Luxe" (SE: 8/728), 1928 (Box 1)
    - Excelsior, Photographs (Box 1)
    - Excelsior, Misc. (Box 1)
    - Germain, "Photograph – 1st Series Germain" (Box 1)
    - Germain, "Germain Chainless"(SE: 3/61), 1897–1898 (Box 1)
    - Germain, "Societe Anonyme de Ateliers Germain", 1909 (Box 1)
    - Germain, "Germain"(SE: 4/62), c. 1909 (Box 1)
    - Germain, Photographs, 1913 (Box 1)
    - Germain, Misc. (Box 1)
    - Impera, Road Tests (Box 1)
    - Metallurgique, "1912 Metallurgique"(SE: 3/65) (Box 1)
    - Metallurgique, "Auto Metallurgique"(SE: 6/395), 1922 (Box 1)
    - Metallurgique, "Auto Metallurgique"(SE: 7/396), 1923-1924 (Box 1)
    - Minerva, "Automobiles 'Minerva'"(SE: 1/68), 1909 (Box 1)
    - Minerva, "Minerva 11 Sans Soupapes 1911"(SE: 2/69) (Box 1)
    - Minerva, "Minerva Sans Soupapes 1913" (Box 1)
    - Minerva, "La Sans Soupapes Belge Minerva"(SE: 4/397), 1920; (2 copies) (Box 1)
    - Minerva, "Minerva" 1926 (SE: 10/403a) (Box 1)
    - Minerva, "Minerva the Goddess of Automobiles"(SE: 11/404), 1926 (Box 1)
    - Minerva, "Minerva"(SE: 13/731), 1927–1928 (Box 1)
    - Minerva, "Minerva the Goddess...Suppl. Catalogue", 1928 (Box 1)
    - Minerva, "Minerva"(SE: 15/733), 1928–1929 (Box 1)
    - Minerva, "Minerva Season 1929"(SE: 12/735) (Box 1)
    - Minerva, "New Minerva Models", 1929 (Oct. 4) (Box 1)
    - Minerva, "Minerva 17 PK", 1931-1932 (Box 1)
    - Minerva, "Minerva"(SE: 20/738), 1932 (Box 1)
    - Minerva, "Minerva 8 Zyl Type '4000 Kurz'"(SE: 22/740), 1931–1932 (Box 1)
    - Minerva, "De Nieuwe 25 PK–8 CYL."(SE: 24/1063), 1933 (Box 1)
    - Minerva, "Minerva 1933"(SE: 25/1064) (Box 1)
    - Minerva, Photographs (Box 1)
    - Minerva, Misc. (Box 1)
    - Pipe, "Automobiles Pipe"(SE: 2/72), 1914 (Box 1)
    - Minerva, "Une Automobile de Qualité..."(SE: 6/399), 1922 (Box 24 (Oversize))
    - Minerva, "Minerva"(SE: 8/401), 1924 (Box 24 (Oversize))
    - Minerva, "Minerva"(SE: 9/402), 1925 (Box 24 (Oversize))
    - Minerva, "Minerva"(SE: 12/730), 1927 (Box 24 (Oversize))
    - Minerva, "Minerva"(SE: 12/730), 1927 (Box 24 (Oversize))
  - Czechoslovakia
    - Aero, Misc (Box 1)
    - Praga, "Praga Alfa", 1932 (Box 1)
    - Praga, Misc. (Box 1)
    - Skoda, Misc (Box 1)
    - Tatra, "Etablissements Tatra...", c. 1927 (Box 1)
    - Tatra, "Tatra Sechszylinder..."(SE: 4/1067), 1933–1934 (Box 1)
    - Tatra, "Tatra 177 la Voiture Elegante", 1934-1935 (Box 1)
    - Tatra, "Der Wagen der Zukunft Tatra Type 77"(SE: 8/1071), 1935 (Box 1)
    - Tatra, "Automobile aerodynamique Tatra 87..."(SE: 12/1075), 1939 (Box 1)
    - Tatra, "Tatra 87", 1946–1947 (Box 1)
    - Tatra, "Tatra 87", 1946–1947 (Box 1)
    - Tatra, "Tatraplan", 1948; (2 copies – variant) (Box 1)
    - Tatra, "Tatraplan", 1951 (Box 1)
    - Tatra, Photographs (Box 1)
    - Tatra, Misc. (Box 1)
    - Walter, Misc. (Box 1)
  - Denmark
    - Hansa, Misc. (Box 1)
  - France
    - Amilcar, "Amilcar", 1928 (Box 1)
    - Amilcar, "Amilcar", 1932 (Box 1)
    - Amilcar, "Amilcar", 1937 (Box 1)
    - Amilcar, Misc. (Box 1)
    - Ballot, "Ballot"(SE: 3/412), 1922–1923 (Box 1)
    - Ballot, "Les Douze Commandments...Ballot", c. 1923 (Box 1)
    - Ballot, "Celles qu'on...Les Voitures Ballot"(SE: 4/749), 1927–1928 (Box 1)
    - Ballot, "Celles qu'on...Ballot LA 8 Cylindres"(SE: 7/752), 1929 (Box 1)
    - Ballot, Misc. (Box 1)
    - Berliet, "Automobiles Berliet"(SE: 1/74), 1907 (Box 1)
    - Berliet, "Berliet"(SE: 2/75), 1908 (Box 1)
    - Berliet, "Automobiles Berliet Lyon Paris"(SE: 5/78), 1914 (Box 1)
    - Berliet, "Automobiles Berliet"(SE: 6/413), 1925 (Box 1)
    - Berliet, Misc. (Box 1)
    - Brasier, "Voiturette George Richard"(SE: 1/2a), 1899–1900 (Box 1)
    - Brasier, "Richard–Brasier, The French Car"(SE: 2/79), 1904 (Box 1)
    - Brasier, "Le Trefte a Quatre Feuilles...", 1907 (Box 1)
    - Brasier, "Automobiles Brasier"(SE: 5/82), 1910 (Dec. 15) (Box 1)
    - Brasier, "Automobiles Brasier 1913"(SE: 7/84) (Box 1)
    - Brasier, "Evangile du Trefle a 4 Feuilles"(SE: 6/83), 1913 (Box 1)
    - Brasier, "Automobiles Brasier"(SE: 8/85), 1914 (Box 1)
    - Bucciali, "Automobiles Bucciali Freres Paris", 1928–1929 (Box 1)
    - Bucciali, "Automobiles Bucciali 16 et 8 cylindres"(SE: 1/754), 1930–1931 (Box 1)
    - Bucciali, "Automobiles Bucciali"(SE: 2/755), 1931–1932 (Box 1)
    - Bucciali, Renderings (Box 1)
    - Bucciali, Misc. (Box 1)
    - Bugatti, "Ettore Bugatti"(SE: 1/86), 1911 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Ettore Bugatti"(SE: 1/86) (facsimile printed in 1962), 1911 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti"(SE: 4/415), 1925 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti"(SE: 5/416), 1926 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti", 1926–1927 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti les 7 merveilles du monde..."(SE: 7/757), 1927 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti la nouvelle 3 litres", 1927–1928 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti"(SE: 8/758), 1927–1928 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "A Road Trial of the 23.6 h.p. Three Litre", 1928 (Nov. 29) (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti"(SE: 9/759), 1929 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Blueprint – Chassis Bugatti Type 46", c. 1930 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Sports Model – 8 Cylinder...Type 57.5", c. 1930s (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti Coachwork 1930"(SE: 10/760) (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Der Wagen Der Anspruchsvollen"(SE: 11/761), c. 1931 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Blueprint – Chassis Bugatti Type 55", 1931 (Oct. 21) (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti"(SE: 13/763), 1931 (Oct.) (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti"(SE: 14/764), 1932 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti"(SE: 14/764), 1932 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Les Chassis 19 C.V. Type 49", 1932 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti 'Royal' Specification", c. 1932 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Ettore Bugatti"(SE: 16/766), c. 1932 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "A New Bugatti Sports Car", 1932 (June 14) (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti Type 57 3L300"(SE: 19/1080a), 1933–1934 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti"(SE: 19/1080b), 1934 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti"(SE: 19/1080c), 1934 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "La 3 Lit.300 Type 57", c. 1935 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti"(SE: 20/1081), 1935–1936 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti"(SE: 21/1082), 1936 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti", 1937 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti"(SE: 22/1083a), 1937 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Le pursang de l'automobile"(SE: 23/1084), 1938 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti"(SE: 24/1085), 1938 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "57, Modeles 1939"(SE: 25/1086) (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, "Bugatti"(SE: 24/1085), 1938 (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, Photographs (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, Renderings (Box 2)
    - Bugatti, Misc. (Box 2)
    - Charron, Girardot, Voigt, "C.G.V."(SE: 2/89), 1904 (Box 2)
    - Charron, Girardot, Voigt, "Charron, Girardot, Voigt"(SE: 3/90), 1905 (1er Novembre) (Box 2)
    - Charron, Girardot, Voigt, "Charron LD", 1909 (Box 2)
    - Charron, Girardot, Voigt, "Charron Limited 1913"(SE: 6/93) (Box 2)
    - Citroën, "LA 22 Huit Cylindres..."(photocopy), 1934–1935 (Box 2)
    - Citroën, "The Super Modern Car", 1935 (Box 2)
    - Citroën, "Front Wheel Drive – The 'Six–Cylinder'", c. 1953 (Box 2)
    - Citroën, "Citroën", 1970 (Box 2)
    - Citroën, Road Tests (Box 2)
    - Cottin & Desgouttes, "Automobiles Cottin & Desgouttes"(SE: 2/95), 1914 (Box 2)
    - Cottin & Desgouttes, "Automobiles Cottin & Desgouttes"(SE: 3/418), 1921–1922 (Box 2)
    - Cottin & Desgouttes, "LA 6 Cylindres Type Leger", 1924 (Box 2)
    - Cottin & Desgouttes, "Gagnet le Grand Prix..."(SE: 4/419), 1925 (Box 2)
    - Cottin & Desgouttes, Misc. (Box 2)
    - Decauville, "L'Automobile Decauville"(SE: 1/5), 1898 (Box 2)
    - DeDion Bouton, "Voitures et Motocycles..."(SE: 1/101), 1902 (Box 2)
    - DeDion Bouton, "Automobiles DeDion Bouton"(SE: 2/102), 1903 (Box 2)
    - DeDion Bouton, "Automobiles DeDion Bouton"(SE: 3/103), 1908 (Box 2)
    - DeDion Bouton, "DeDion Bouton"(SE: 5/105), 1914 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Delage", 1913 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "The Six Cylinder Type C.O."(SE: 2/422a) (includes facsimile), 1920 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Delage LA 6 Cylindres"(SE: 3/423), c. 1921 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Delage LA Six-Cylinders"(SE: 8/771), 1926–1927 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Ne faire qu'une..."(SE: 1/421), 1919–1920 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Delage", 1923 (Mar. 1) (Box 2)
    - Delage, "The 6 Cylinder Delage Chassis"(SE: 11/774), 1929 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Delage", c. 1930s (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Delage, the D8"(SE: 14/777), 1930 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "The Straight Eight D8 Delage"(SE: 15/778), 1931 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "LA D8 Delage Huit Cylindres"(SE: 15/778), 1931 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Les Delage aux Concours d'Elegance"(SE: 16/779), 1931 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Delage"(SE: 17/780), 1931–1932 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "D8 Delage"(SE: 18/781), 1932 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "D8S Delage"(SE: 19/782), 1932 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Delage Aux Concours D'Elegance"(SE: 20/783), 1932 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "D8S Delage"(SE: 23/1089), 1933–1934 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "D8S Delage"(photocopies), 1933–1934 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Delage D6.11"(SE: 25/1091), 1933–1934 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "D4 La Belle Voiture Francaise", 1933 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "LA D6–11 Delage"(SE: 26/1092), 1934 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "La Belle Voiture Francaise"(SE: 24/1090), 1933 (Sept.) (Box 2)
    - Delage, "D8.15 Delage"(SE: 27/1093), 1934 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "D–6 D8–85 Delage"(SE: 30/1096), 1935 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Delage"(SE: 31/1097), 1935 (Sept.) (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Delage"(SE: 32/1098), 1937 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Delage 1937"(SE: 33/1099) (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Delage"(SE: 34/1100), 1938–1939 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Haute Expression de la..."(SE: 35/1101), 1939 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Elegance–Comfort–Vitesse", 1939 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Delage Les 3 Litres", c. 1949 (Box 2)
    - Delage, "Delage D 6–3 Litres", c. 1952 (Box 2)
    - Delage, Photographs (Box 2)
    - Delage, Renderings (Box 2)
    - Delage, Misc. (Box 2)
    - Delahaye, "Automobiles Delahaye"(SE: 2/107), 1908 (Box 2)
    - Delahaye, "Les Quat'–z–Arts offert...", 1912–1913 (Box 2)
    - Delahaye, "Les super–deluxe Delahaye"(SE: 4/1102), 1935 (Box 2)
    - Delahaye, "Les Superdeluxe Delahaye"(SE: 5/1103), 1935–1936 (Box 2)
    - Delahaye, "Delahaye 1936–1937"(SE: 6/1104) (Box 2)
    - Delahaye, "Delahaye 1937–1938"(SE: 7/1105) (Box 2)
    - Delahaye, "Delahaye", 1938 (Box 2)
    - Delahaye, "Delahaye Pour l'Elite"(SE: 8/1106), 1939 (Box 2)
    - Delahaye, "Delahaye 1939"(SE: 9/1107) (Box 2)
    - Delahaye, "Delahaye", 1948–1949 (Box 2)
    - Delahaye, "Delahaye Delage GFA", c. 1950 (Box 2)
    - Delahaye, "GFA Delahaye Type 175", c. 1951 (Box 2)
    - Delahaye, "Delahaye", c. 1939–1940 (Box 2)
    - Delahaye, "Delahaye Delage–Symbole...", c. 1951 (Box 2)
    - Delahaye, Photographs (Box 2)
    - Delahaye, Road Tests (Box 2)
    - Delahaye, Misc. (Box 2)
    - Delaunay Belleville, "Etablissements...Salon de 1904"(SE: 1/109) (Box 3)
    - Delaunay Belleville, "Delaunay Belleville Automobiles..."(SE: 2/110), 1907 (Box 3)
    - Delaunay Belleville, "Delaunay Belleville Automobiles 1908"(SE: 3/111) (Box 3)
    - Delaunay Belleville, "Palais de la Automobile Importers...", 1908 (Box 3)
    - Delaunay Belleville, "Brewster & Co. Delaunay Belleville"(SE: 4/112), c. 1910 (Box 3)
    - Delaunay Belleville, "Delaunay Belleville 1911"(SE: 5/113) (Box 3)
    - Delaunay Belleville, "Automobiles Delaunay Belleville"(SE: 7/115), 1913–1914, 1914-1915 (Box 3)
    - Delaunay Belleville, "Delaunay Belleville Automobiles 1921–1922"(SE: 9/428) (Box 3)
    - Delaunay Belleville, "Delaunay Belleville 1923"(SE: 10/429), 1922 (Oct.) (Box 3)
    - Delaunay Belleville, "La Societe des Automobiles...SA 12 HP 1923"(SE: 11/430) (Box 3)
    - Delaunay Belleville, "Description des Chassis...1924"(SE: 12/431), 1923 (Oct.) (Box 3)
    - Delaunay Belleville, "Automobiles…12 C.V. Type 1925" (Box 3)
    - Delaunay Belleville, "Delaunay Belleville", 1930 (Box 3)
    - Delaunay Belleville, "Delaunay 8 6 Belleville"(SE: 15/786), 1931 (Box 3)
    - Delaunay Belleville, "Automobiles Delaunay Belleville"(SE: 16/1108), 1933 (Box 3)
    - Delaunay Belleville, "Delaunay Belleville Modeles 1935"(SE: 17/1109), 1934 (Oct.) (Box 3)
    - Delaunay Belleville, "Delaunay Belleville", 1936 (Box 3)
    - Delaunay Belleville, Misc. (Box 3)
    - Derby, "Automobiles Derby 4 cylindres 6 cylindres"(SE: 1/787), c. 1930 (Box 3)
    - Derby, "Derby"(SE: 2/788), 1932-1933 (Box 3)
    - Derby, Photographs (Box 3)
    - Facel S.A., "Facel Vega", c. 1958 (Box 3)
    - Facel S.A., "Facellia F2 ET F2S Facel Vega Paris", c. 1959 (Box 3)
    - Facel S.A., "Facel III", 1963 (Box 3)
    - Facel S.A., Road Tests (Box 3)
    - Facel S.A., Misc. (Box 3)
    - Farman, "Elegant sous tous ses..."(SE: 2/434), 1922 (Box 3)
    - Farman, "Farman La Voiture..."(SE: 3/435), 1922 (Box 3)
    - Farman, "Particularites Mecaniques..."(SE: 8/441), c. 1925 (Box 3)
    - Farman, "The 6 Cylinder Farman"(SE: 6/439), 1925 (Box 3)
    - Farman, "LA 6 Cylindres Farman"(SE: 9/442), 1926 (Box 3)
    - Farman, "La Nouvelle Farman", c. 1927 (Box 3)
    - Farman, "LA 6 Cylindres Farman"(SE: 10/789), c. 1928 (Box 3)
    - Farman, "Automobiles Farman Chassis 40 CV", 1930 (Oct.) (Box 3)
    - Farman, "Farman"(SE: 12/791), 1931 (Box 3)
    - Farman, Misc. (Box 3)
    - Gallia, "Voitures Electriques 'Gallia'"(SE: 1/116), 1906 (Box 3)
    - Gardner–Serpollet, "Automobiles a Vapeur...", 1903 (Box 3)
    - George Irat, "Quelques Suggestions..."(SE: 2/446), c. 1926 (Box 3)
    - George Irat, "Automobiles Georges Irat"(SE: 3/792), c. 1927 (Box 3)
    - George Irat, "Georges Irat"(SE: 4/793), 1928 (Box 3)
    - George Irat, "Georges Irat"(SE: 5/794), c. 1928-1929 (Box 3)
    - George Irat, "La Voiture de L'elite"(SE: 6/1111), c. 1935 (Box 3)
    - George Irat, Misc. (Box 3)
    - Gobron, "Automobiles Gobron-Brillie"(SE: 1/117), 1905 (Box 3)
    - Gobron, "Automobiles Gobron-Brillie"(SE: 3/119), 1907 (Box 3)
    - Gobron, "Automobiles Gobron"(SE: 2/118), 1907 (Box 3)
    - Hautier, "Automobiles Hautier"(SE: 1/121), 1903 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza"(SE: 1/122), 1911 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza"(SE: 3/124), 1912 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Automobiles Hispano–Suiza"(photocopy), 1912-1913 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "La Reine de la Route"(SE: 4/25), 1914 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza"(SE: 5/447) (photocopy), 1919–1920 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza – 1922"(SE: 6/448) (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza la reine de la route"(SE: 7/449), 1923 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza – 1924"(SE: 10/452) (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "La Reine de la Route", 1924–1925 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza", c. 1925 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza"(SE: 11/453), c. 1925 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza Clark D. Pease Inc."(SE: 12/795), 1927 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza", 1927–1928 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza", c. 1928 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza"(SE: 14/797), 1930 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza"(SE: 14/797) (variant), 1930 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza", 1931–1932 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano"Suiza", 1931–1932 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Ballot H.S. 26 Licence..."(SE: 15/798), 1931–1932 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "L'Embleme de la Perfection..."(SE: 17/800), 1932 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "H.S. Junior 1932"(SE: 18/801) (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "LA 54 C.V. 12 Cylindres", 1934 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza 54/220–12 Cylindres", 1934 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Autocar Road Tests...", 1934 (Mar. 30) (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Autocar Road Tests...", 1934 (Nov. 30) (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza 30 cv.6 CYL"(SE: 20/1113a), 1935 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza 30/120 H.P. 6 CYL"(SE: 20/1113b), 1935 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Hispano–Suiza 30 CV. 6 CYL"(SE: 21/1114a), 1936 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, "Registry of Cars – Directory of Owners", 2004 (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, Photographs (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, Renderings (Box 3)
    - Hispano–Suiza, Misc. (Box 3)
    - Hotchkiss, "Hotchkiss & CIE Automobiles"(SE: 2/127), 1908 (Box 3)
    - Hotchkiss, "Hotchkiss 1912"(SE: 3/128) (Box 3)
    - Hotchkiss, "1922 Automobiles Hotchkiss"(SE: 5/454) (Box 3)
    - Hotchkiss, "LA 12 Hotchkiss 1926"(SE: 6/455) (Box 3)
    - Hotchkiss, "Pour la ville pour la route"(SE: 7/802), 1928 (Box 3)
    - Hotchkiss, "Hotchkiss Qualite Totale"(SE: 15/118), 1935 (Box 3)
    - Hotchkiss, "Hotchkiss"(SE: 16/119), 1936 (Box 3)
    - Hotchkiss, "Automobiles Hotchkiss Salon 1936"(SE: 17/120), 1937 (Box 3)
    - Hotchkiss, "The 1939 Hotchkiss"(SE: 18/1121) (Box 3)
    - Hotchkiss, "Style Hotchkiss 1951" (Box 3)
    - Hotchkiss, "'Antheor' Cabriolet…Henri Chapron Hotchkiss", 1951 (Box 3)
    - Hotchkiss, Road Tests (Box 3)
    - Hotchkiss, Misc. (Box 3)
    - Krieger, "Voiture Electrique Francaise Systeme Krieger"(SE: 1/8), 1898 (Box 3)
    - Lombard, "Automobiles Lombard"(SE: 1/806), c. 1928 (Box 3)
    - Lombard, Misc. (Box 3)
    - Lorraine Dietrich/De Dietrich & Cie., "1907 Societe Lorraine des Anciens..."(SE: 4/132) (Box 3)
    - Lorraine Dietrich/De Dietrich & Cie., "Societe Lorraine, De Dietrich & Cie"(SE: 7/135), 1912 (Box 3)
    - Lorraine Dietrich/De Dietrich & Cie., "Lorraine Dietrich 1913"(SE: 8/136) (Box 3)